<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><metadata>
    <idinfo>
        <citation>
            <citeinfo>
                <origin/>
                <pubdate>20200327</pubdate>
                <title>Category One (C1) Waters of New Jersey, Edition 20200327 (Hydr_water_stream_C1) (Web Mercator ArcGIS Online Service)</title>
                <geoform>vector digital data</geoform>
                <pubinfo>
                    <pubplace/>
                    <publish>NJ Department of Environmental Protection (NJDEP)</publish>
                </pubinfo>
                <othercit>This data was generated by a reselect of C1 Waters (CATEGORY Field) from Surface Water Quality Standards (swqs) data.</othercit>
                <onlink>https://www.nj.gov/dep/gis/digidownload/zips/OpenData/Hydr_water_stream_C1.zip</onlink>
            </citeinfo>
        </citation>
        <descript>
            <abstract>Advisory: C1 Waters are a reselect of the Surface Water Quality Standard's (SWQS) CATEGORY attribute. The information contained in this metadata record reflects the SWQS data. As stated in this metadata record's Use Constraints section, NJDEP makes no representations of any kind, including, but not limited to, the warranties of merchantability or fitness for a particular use, nor are any such warranties to be implied with respect to the digital data layers furnished hereunder. NJDEP assumes no responsibility to maintain them in any manner or form. By downloading this data, user agrees to the data use constraints listed within this metadata record. This data is a digital representation of New Jersey's Surface Water Quality Standards in accordance with "Surface Water Quality Standards for New Jersey Waters" as designated in N.J.A.C. 7:9 B. The Surface Water Quality Standards (SWQS) establish the designated uses to be achieved and specify the water quality (criteria) necessary to protect the State's waters. Designated uses include potable water, propagation of fish and wildlife, recreation, agricultural and industrial supplies, and navigation. These are reflected in use classifications assigned to specific waters. The line-work has been broken/altered to reflect the descriptions specified at N.J.A.C. 7:9B-1.15. When interpreting the stream classifications and anti-degradation designations, the descriptions specified in the SWQS at N.J.A.C. 7:9B-1.15 always take precedence. The GIS layer reflects the stream classifications and anti-degradation designations adopted as of the publication date and is supplemental only and is not legally binding.</abstract>
            <purpose>The hydrography stream network was created to support water management and monitoring activities within NJDEP, and to be a valuable layer for computerized cartographic products.</purpose>
        </descript>
        <timeperd>
            <timeinfo>
                <sngdate>
                    <caldate>20200327</caldate>
                </sngdate>
            </timeinfo>
            <current>Ground condition</current>
        </timeperd>
        <status>
            <progress>In work</progress>
            <update>As needed</update>
        </status>
        <spdom>
            <bounding>
                <westbc>-75.555873</westbc>
                <eastbc>-73.91661</eastbc>
                <northbc>41.352022</northbc>
                <southbc>38.942769</southbc>
            </bounding>
        </spdom>
        <keywords>
            <theme>
                <themekt>ISO 19115 Topic Category</themekt>
                <themekey>inlandWaters</themekey>
            </theme>
            <theme>
                <themekt>User</themekt>
                <themekey>c1waters</themekey>
                <themekey>Hydr_water_stream_C1</themekey>
            </theme>
            <theme>
                <themekt>None</themekt>
                <themekey>rivers</themekey>
                <themekey>swqs</themekey>
                <themekey>streams</themekey>
                <themekey>surfacewater</themekey>
                <themekey>drainage</themekey>
                <themekey>standards</themekey>
                <themekey>C1</themekey>
                <themekey>water quality</themekey>
                <themekey>hydrography</themekey>
            </theme>
            <place>
                <placekt>None</placekt>
                <placekey>NJ</placekey>
                <placekey>New Jersey</placekey>
            </place>
            <temporal>
                <tempkt>None</tempkt>
                <tempkey>2008</tempkey>
            </temporal>
        </keywords>
        <accconst>In most cases, a downloadable shapefile (.zip) version of this layer is also available. Information to download the shapefile can be found in the Distribution Section of this metadata record. This data layer is shown in the NJDEP's NJ-GeoWeb mapping application accessible through the Online Linkage: https://www.nj.gov/dep/gis/geowebsplash.htm</accconst>
        <useconst>New Jersey Department of Environmental Protection (NJDEP) Data Distribution Agreement. The data provided herein are distributed subject to the following conditions and restrictions: NJDEP assumes no responsibility to maintain them in any manner or form and disclaims any duty or obligation to either maintain availability of or to update the data. Terms of Agreement 1. All data is provided, as is, without any representation or warranty of any kind, implied, expressed or statutory including, but not limited to, the warranties of non-infringement of third party rights, title, merchantability or fitness for a particular use, freedom from computer virus nor are any such warranties to be implied with respect to the digital data layers furnished hereunder. User is responsible for understanding the accuracy limitations of all digital data layers provided herein, as documented in the accompanying cross-reference files (see SUPPLEMENTAL INFORMATION). Any reproduction or manipulation of the above data must ensure that the coordinate reference system remains intact. 2. Digital data received from the NJDEP may not be reproduced or redistributed without all the metadata provided. 3. Any maps, publications, reports, or other documents produced as a result of this project that utilize this digital data will credit the NJDEP's Geographic Information System (GIS) as the source of the data with the following credit/disclaimer: 'This (map/publication/report) was developed using New Jersey Department of Environmental Protection Geographic Information System digital data, but this secondary product has not been verified by NJDEP and is not state-authorized or endorsed.' 4. NJDEP makes no warranty that digital data are free of Copyright or Trademark claims or other restrictions or limitations on free use or display. Making a copy of this data may be subject to the copyright of trademark laws.</useconst>
        <ptcontac>
            <cntinfo>
                <cntorgp>
                    <cntorg>Water Monitoring</cntorg>
                    <cntper>Lager, Leigh</cntper>
                </cntorgp>
                <cntpos>Geographic Information Systems Specialist 2</cntpos>
                <cntaddr>
                    <addrtype>mailing</addrtype>
                    <address>25-35 Arctic Pkwy Eshap/Land Use</address>
                    <city>Ewing Twp</city>
                    <state>NJ</state>
                    <postal>08638</postal>
                </cntaddr>
                <cntvoice>609-943-3266</cntvoice>
                <cntemail>Leigh.Lager@dep.nj.gov</cntemail>
                <cntinst>via email</cntinst>
            </cntinfo>
        </ptcontac>
        <datacred>NJ Department of Environmental Protection (NJDEP), Water Monitoring &amp; Standards (WMS), Bureau of Freshwater and Biological Monitoring (BFBM)</datacred>
        <native>ESRI ArcCatalog 9.2.2.1350</native>
    </idinfo>
    <dataqual>
        <attracc>
            <attraccr>Frequencies run to check for valid attributes. Visual inspection of proof plots.</attraccr>
        </attracc>
        <logic>Based upon 2002 hydrography deliverables, the data were reviewed for correct topological structure.</logic>
        <complete>Linework complete as per the 2002 hydrography deliverables. C1 Waters reselected of the Surface Water Quality Standard's (SWQS) CATEGORY attribute.</complete>
        <posacc>
            <horizpa>
                <horizpar>NMAS at 1:12000 based upon 2002 hydrography.</horizpar>
            </horizpa>
        </posacc>
        <posacc>
            <vertacc>
                <vertaccr>NA</vertaccr>
            </vertacc>
        </posacc>
        <lineage>
            <srcinfo>
                <srccite>
                    <citeinfo>
                        <origin/>
                        <pubdate>20081201</pubdate>
                        <title>NJDEP State Owned, Protected Open Space and Recreation Areas in New Jersey 1:12000</title>
                        <pubinfo>
                            <pubplace/>
                            <publish>Green Acres</publish>
                        </pubinfo>
                        <onlink>https://www.nj.gov/dep/gis/digidownload/zips/statewide/newstate.zip</onlink>
                    </citeinfo>
                </srccite>
                <srcscale>12000</srcscale>
                <typesrc>onLine</typesrc>
                <srctime>
                    <timeinfo>
                        <sngdate>
                            <caldate>20081201</caldate>
                        </sngdate>
                    </timeinfo>
                    <srccurr>ground condition</srccurr>
                </srctime>
                <srccitea>newstate (state open space)</srccitea>
                <srccontr>Stream segments were broken at state park/wildlife management area boundaries where mentioned in the surfacewater quality standards.</srccontr>
            </srcinfo>
            <srcinfo>
                <srccite>
                    <citeinfo>
                        <origin/>
                        <pubdate>20020411</pubdate>
                        <pubtime>unknown</pubtime>
                        <title>Aerial Imagery Acquisition of the State of New Jersey</title>
                        <geoform>remote-sensing image</geoform>
                        <pubinfo>
                            <pubplace/>
                            <publish>Keystone Aerial Surveys</publish>
                        </pubinfo>
                    </citeinfo>
                </srccite>
                <srcscale>2400</srcscale>
                <typesrc>CD-ROM</typesrc>
                <srctime>
                    <timeinfo>
                        <rngdates>
                            <begdate>20020218</begdate>
                            <enddate>20020411</enddate>
                        </rngdates>
                    </timeinfo>
                    <srccurr>ground condition</srccurr>
                </srctime>
                <srccitea>Aerial Photography</srccitea>
                <srccontr>Digital color infrared (CIR) orthophotography of New Jersey in State Plane NAD83 Coordinates, U.S. Survey Feet. The digital orthophotography was produced at a scale of 1:2400 (1"=200') with a 1 foot pixel resolution. The linear streams layer and the polygonal water bodies extracted from the land use/land cover for 2002 was digitized directly from 2002 digital image files.</srccontr>
            </srcinfo>
            <srcinfo>
                <srccite>
                    <citeinfo>
                        <origin/>
                        <pubdate>19940101</pubdate>
                        <title>Pinelands Area Boundary of New Jersey</title>
                        <geoform>vector digital data</geoform>
                        <pubinfo>
                            <pubplace/>
                            <publish>NJDEP</publish>
                        </pubinfo>
                        <onlink>https://www.nj.gov/dep/gis/digidownload/zips/statewide/pinelands.zip</onlink>
                    </citeinfo>
                </srccite>
                <srcscale>24000</srcscale>
                <typesrc>onLine</typesrc>
                <srctime>
                    <timeinfo>
                        <sngdate>
                            <caldate>19940101</caldate>
                        </sngdate>
                    </timeinfo>
                    <srccurr>ground condition</srccurr>
                </srctime>
                <srccitea>pinelands</srccitea>
                <srccontr>Stream segments were broken at pinelands boundaries mentioned in the surfacewater quality standards.</srccontr>
            </srcinfo>
            <procstep>
                <procdesc>The base linework is the hydrography layer derived from the 2002 overflight. Where the standards specified a boundary, the appropriate source data was used to break the line segment to accurately reflect the written standard. The arcs were then coded for their surface water quality standards designation in accordance with "Surface Water Quality Standards for New Jersey Waters" as designated in N.J.A.C. 7:9 B-1. The old SWQS layer was the primary source used to determine attributes. The interpretation of the written text has already been done and was therefore used as a guide. Where the hydrography differed significantly between old and new, the correct entry in the standards was found, interpreted and then applied.</procdesc>
                <procdate>20071019</procdate>
            </procstep>
            <procstep>
                <procdesc>C1 Waters reselected of the Surface Water Quality Standard's (SWQS) CATEGORY attribute.</procdesc>
                <procdate>20080901</procdate>
            </procstep>
            <procstep>
                <procdesc>Various issues addressed.</procdesc>
                <procdate>20081208</procdate>
            </procstep>
            <procstep>
                <procdesc>Various issues addressed.</procdesc>
                <procdate>20090501</procdate>
            </procstep>
            <procstep>
                <procdesc>Various changes made. DRBC entries removed.</procdesc>
                <procdate>20100101</procdate>
            </procstep>
            <procstep>
                <procdesc>Various changes made.</procdesc>
                <procdate>20101201</procdate>
            </procstep>
        </lineage>
    </dataqual>
    <spdoinfo>
        <direct>Vector</direct>
        <ptvctinf>
            <sdtsterm>
                <sdtstype>Complete chain</sdtstype>
                <ptvctcnt>100059</ptvctcnt>
            </sdtsterm>
        </ptvctinf>
    </spdoinfo>
    <eainfo>
        <detailed>
            <enttyp>
                <enttypl>Hydr_water_stream_C1</enttypl>
                <enttypd>C1 Waters from SWQS</enttypd>
                <enttypds>NJDEP</enttypds>
            </enttyp>
            <attr>
                <attrlabl>OBJECTID</attrlabl>
                <attrdef>Internal feature number.</attrdef>
                <attrdefs>ESRI</attrdefs>
                <attrdomv>
                                        					
                    
                    <udom>Sequential unique whole numbers that are automatically generated.</udom>
                                        				
                
                </attrdomv>
            </attr>
            <attr>
                <attrlabl>SITUATION</attrlabl>
                <attrdef>Stream situation</attrdef>
                <attrdefs>NJDEP</attrdefs>
                <attrdomv>
                                        					
                    
                    <edom>
                                                						
                        
                        <edomv>0</edomv>
                                                						
                        
                        <edomvd>Undefined</edomvd>
                                                						
                        
                        <edomvds>NJDEP</edomvds>
                                                					
                    
                    </edom>
                                        				
                
                </attrdomv>
                <attrdomv>
                                        					
                    
                    <edom>
                                                						
                        
                        <edomv>1</edomv>
                                                						
                        
                        <edomvd>Stream. Arc representing visible water that appears as a natural stream course.  This category also includes former ditches that have naturalized and straightened streams (non-ditch). Open water passing under bridges is also captured as a stream.</edomvd>
                                                						
                        
                        <edomvds>NJDEP</edomvds>
                                                					
                    
                    </edom>
                                        				
                
                </attrdomv>
                <attrdomv>
                                        					
                    
                    <edom>
                                                						
                        
                        <edomv>2</edomv>
                                                						
                        
                        <edomvd>Proxy Centerline (PC).  Arc drawn through water polygons to provide continuity with stream arc network for flow modeling purposes.  They do not represent the official centerline of the water body.  Typically, a single PC was mapped through each water feature, excluding side-streams entering into the feature.</edomvd>
                                                						
                        
                        <edomvds>NJDEP</edomvds>
                                                					
                    
                    </edom>
                                        				
                
                </attrdomv>
                <attrdomv>
                                        					
                    
                    <edom>
                                                						
                        
                        <edomv>3</edomv>
                                                						
                        
                        <edomvd>Artificial connector (AC).  Arc representing underground passage of stream through a man-made feature such as a culvert.  Artificial connectors are also mapped where they provide connectivity of the stream network in areas where an underground stream connection can be inferred.  Bridges are not considered artificial connectors.</edomvd>
                                                						
                        
                        <edomvds>NJDEP</edomvds>
                                                					
                    
                    </edom>
                                        				
                
                </attrdomv>
                <attrdomv>
                                        					
                    
                    <edom>
                                                						
                        
                        <edomv>4</edomv>
                                                						
                        
                        <edomvd>Ditch.  Man-made open water features created for the purpose of moving water from one location to another to drain wetlands, prevent flooding, or provide drainage for urban areas. Typically found in wetlands, near roadways, and in urban areas.</edomvd>
                                                						
                        
                        <edomvds>NJDEP</edomvds>
                                                					
                    
                    </edom>
                                        				
                
                </attrdomv>
                <attrdomv>
                                        					
                    
                    <edom>
                                                						
                        
                        <edomv>5</edomv>
                                                						
                        
                        <edomvd>Invisible Stream.  Arc representing a stream in NJDEP's existing hydrology coverage that is not visible on the 2002 imagery, yet the surrounding area appears to support the continued presence of the stream, i.e. undisturbed wetland and/or upland vegetation, no obvious man-made or natural disturbance that would impact the existing stream flow.</edomvd>
                                                						
                        
                        <edomvds>NJDEP</edomvds>
                                                					
                    
                    </edom>
                                        				
                
                </attrdomv>
            </attr>
            <attr>
                <attrlabl>CATEGORY</attrlabl>
                <attrdef>Category is a compendium of all surface water classification designations for a given water body. Category describes a stream's surface water classification in terms of its general surface water class, its antidegradation status and its trout water status.</attrdef>
                <attrdefs>NJDEP</attrdefs>
                <attrdomv>
                                        					
                    
                    <codesetd>
                                                						
                        
                        <codesetn>Surface Water Quality Standards for New Jersey Waters, as designated in N.J.A.C. 7:9 B.</codesetn>
                                                						
                        
                        <codesets>NJDEP</codesets>
                                                					
                    
                    </codesetd>
                                        				
                
                </attrdomv>
            </attr>
            <attr>
                <attrlabl>NAMECK</attrlabl>
                <attrdef>Name of stream or description of stream in relation to a named stream.</attrdef>
                <attrdefs>NJDEP</attrdefs>
                <attrdomv>
                                        					
                    
                    <udom>unique</udom>
                                        				
                
                </attrdomv>
            </attr>
            <attr>
                <attrlabl>REFER</attrlabl>
                <attrdef>Reference number from swqs database</attrdef>
                <attrdefs>NJDEP</attrdefs>
                <attrdomv>
                                        					
                    
                    <udom>unique</udom>
                                        				
                
                </attrdomv>
            </attr>
            <attr>
                <attrlabl>FISHGAMENM</attrlabl>
                <attrdef>Supplemental Name Information from F&amp;W or other sources</attrdef>
                <attrdefs>NJDEP</attrdefs>
                <attrdomv>
                                        					
                    
                    <udom>unique</udom>
                                        				
                
                </attrdomv>
            </attr>
            <attr>
                <attrlabl>DATE_EFFECTIVE</attrlabl>
                <attrdef>Date published in NJ Register</attrdef>
                <attrdefs>NJDEP</attrdefs>
                <attrdomv>
                                        					
                    
                    <udom>unique</udom>
                                        				
                
                </attrdomv>
            </attr>
            <attr>
                <attrlabl>SHAPE</attrlabl>
                <attrdef>Feature geometry.</attrdef>
                <attrdefs>ESRI</attrdefs>
                <attrdomv>
                                        					
                    
                    <udom>Coordinates defining the features.</udom>
                                        				
                
                </attrdomv>
            </attr>
            <attr>
                <attrlabl>SHAPE.LEN</attrlabl>
                <attrdef>Length of feature</attrdef>
                <attrdefs>ESRI</attrdefs>
                <attrdomv>
                                        					
                    
                    <udom>Positive real numbers that are automatically generated.</udom>
                                        				
                
                </attrdomv>
            </attr>
        </detailed>
    </eainfo>
    <distinfo>
        <distrib>
            <cntinfo>
                <cntorgp>
                    <cntorg>NJDEP/DOIT/Bureau of GIS</cntorg>
                    <cntper>GIS Help Desk</cntper>
                </cntorgp>
                <cntaddr>
                    <addrtype>mailing and physical</addrtype>
                    <address>401 East State Street</address>
                    <city>Trenton</city>
                    <state>NJ</state>
                    <postal>08625</postal>
                </cntaddr>
                <cntvoice>(609) 777-0672</cntvoice>
                <cntfax>(609) 292-7900</cntfax>
                <cntemail>gisnet@dep.nj.gov</cntemail>
            </cntinfo>
        </distrib>
        <resdesc>Downloadable Data</resdesc>
        <distliab>This organization provides the geographic data "as is". This organization makes no guarantee or warranty concerning the accuracy of information contained in the geographic data. Also, this organization makes no warranty either expressed or implied, regarding the condition of the product or its fitness for any particular purpose. The burden for determining fitness for use lies entirely with the user. Although these files have been processed successfully on computers at this organization, no warranty is made by this organization regarding the use of these data on any other system, nor does the fact of distribution constitute or imply any such warranty. See also "Use Constraints" for additional distribution and/or data use requirements.</distliab>
        <stdorder>
            <digform>
                <digtinfo>
                    <formname>DEP distributes ESRI .SHP and/or GDB. Some data may be NJ GeoWeb "display only" layers.</formname>
                    <formvern>latest version</formvern>
                    <filedec>WinZip</filedec>
                </digtinfo>
                <digtopt>
                    <onlinopt>
                        <computer>
                            <networka>
                                <networkr>https://www.nj.gov/dep/gis</networkr>
                            </networka>
                        </computer>
                        <computer>
                            <networka>
                                <networkr>https://www.nj.gov/dep/gis/geowebsplash.htm</networkr>
                            </networka>
                        </computer>
                    </onlinopt>
                </digtopt>
            </digform>
            <fees>None</fees>
            <ordering>All available NJDEP public GIS data can be downloaded for free. Some data shown in NJGeoWeb application may not yet be available for download due to various data or distribution issues. Please email gisnet@dep.nj.gov with any data distribution questions.</ordering>
        </stdorder>
    </distinfo>
    <metainfo>
        <metd>20200327</metd>
        <metc>
            <cntinfo>
                <cntorgp>
                    <cntorg>NJDEP/WMS/BFBM</cntorg>
                    <cntper>Leigh Lager</cntper>
                </cntorgp>
                <cntpos>GIS Specialist</cntpos>
                <cntaddr>
                    <addrtype>mailing and physical</addrtype>
                    <address>401 East State Street, Box 428</address>
                    <city>Trenton</city>
                    <state>New Jersey</state>
                    <postal>08625</postal>
                </cntaddr>
                <cntvoice>609-292-0427</cntvoice>
                <cntfax>609-633-1095</cntfax>
                <cntemail>Leigh.Lager@dep.nj.gov</cntemail>
            </cntinfo>
        </metc>
        <metstdn>FGDC Content Standard for Digital Geospatial Metadata</metstdn>
        <metstdv>FGDC-STD-001-1998</metstdv>
        <mettc>local time</mettc>
    </metainfo>
</metadata>
